Welcome to the first coding quiz in this lesson.
欢迎来本课的第一个编程小练习
Let's go ahead and put what we have learned into C++.
我们要在 C++ 中实践已经学过的方法
In this quiz you will write a small function that generates sigma points.
在这个小练习中 你需要写一个小函数来生成 sigma点
I've prepared the template for you and
我已经为你准备好了模板
I would like to quickly make you familiar with it.
希望你能够迅速上手
You will be working on a function called GenerateSigmaPoints.
你需要编写一个名为 GenerateSigmaPoints 的函数
Which receives a pointer to a matrix as input.
它的收到的输入
This is where you are expected to write your result.
是指向一个矩阵的指针
I will show you how this works in the end of the function.
我会在函数末尾讲述其原理
This time, we will consider the complete state of the CTRV model.
这次 我们要考虑 CTRV 模型的完整状态
So we set the state dimension n_x to 5.
因此 我们把状态大小 n_x 设为 5
Here we set the design parameter lambda to 3- n_x as suggested before.
这里 我们把设计参数 lambda 设为 3-n_x 这个之前说过
Then we set the example set x and
然后 我们为案例集合 x 和
the example covariance matrix P to some realistic values.
案例协方差矩阵 P 设一些现实数值
Now we create a matrix called Xsig.
现在 我们创建一个叫做 Xsig 的矩阵
This is a matrix with five rows and 11 columns.
这个矩阵有 5 行 11 列
This is where I want you to store the sigma points later.
后面生成的 sigma点会放在这个矩阵里
Now here, I give you a little help for
这里 我给了点小提示
calculating the square root matrix of the covariance matrix P.
帮助你计算矩阵 P 的协方差的平方根矩阵
What you see here are two function calls which are part of the Eigen library.
这里你可以看到两个函数调用 它们是 Eigen 库的一部分
It performs a Cholesky decomposition and provides the result we need.
它执行 Cholesky 分解并提供我们需要的结果
Feel free to Google this approach, if you want to know more about it.
你可以谷歌搜索该方法 进一步了解
This is where you're supposed to put your code.
你的代码要放在这里
I would like you to calculate all 11 sigma points and
你需要计算所有 11 个 sigma点
fill the columns of Xsig with the sigma points.
并使用 sigma点填充 Xsig 各栏
One thing is important, when you fill this matrix,
填充矩阵时 有一点很重要
use the same ordering of sigma points as I showed you in the video,
sigma点的顺序必须和我在视频中展示的一样
to make sure the evaluation works.
这样才能保证评估的正常进行
In the end, the result will be printed, so you can check if it's realistic.
在最后 结果会打印出来 方便你检查其是否现实
We received the pointer Xsig_out as input.
我们收到了Xsig_out 指针作为输入
It points to a matrix.
它指向一个矩阵
This is how we put our result into this matrix.
这里 我们把结果放入矩阵
Please don't change anything outside the student area
请不要修改学员代码区域以外的任何内容
to make sure your result can be evaluated correctly.
否则结果评估可能出现问题
Some of the challenges of these programming assignments are related to
这些编程作业的部分挑战
handling rows and columns of matrices with the Eigen library.
涉及如何处理 Eigen 库的栏和矩阵
Check link to the Eigen cheat sheet in the assignment description,
请查看作业描述中的 Eigen 参考表格
that will help you a lot.
里面有很多有用信息